

3	90 537 513 45 29
\searrow	alporan@windowslive.com
	www.alporan.github.io/blog
in	www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran

--

PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing and maintaining software systems. Quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Strong problem solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-manage during personal projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Turkish Airlines, 2017-Present

Development, testing, and maintenance of mainframe applications for airline reservation & ticketing systems. Main responsibilities;

- Developing applications using JAVA, IBM High Level Assembler and Agile practices.
- Maintenance of code base and database records.
- Solving dumps and system errors.
- Automating manual tasks and test cases with Python Programming Language.
- Providing support for open systems' teams utilizing mainframe programs.
- Conducting code reviews.

IT INTERN

Arçelik A.Ş., Jun 2015-Aug 2015

This tenure has provided valuable insight in how an effective IT operation should be maintained. Main responsibilities;

- Providing support for the IT team in the maintenance of hardware & software systems.
- Conducting and documenting various test cases.

ENGINEERING INTERN

GUMUSH AeroSpace, Jan 2015-May 2015

A micro-satellite (can-sat) project had been carried out with a team of 3 people.

Main responsibilities;

- Implementation of sensor and communication systems of the satellite.
- Conducting various test scenarios.
- Documentation and presentation of the project.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE, Information Technologies

Sakarya University, 2018-2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Istanbul Technical University, 2011-2015

PROJECTS

Personal Webpage

Static webpage for presenting my portfolio and blogging.

Tools: Jekyll, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Link:** https://alporan.github.io/blog

Clinic Appointment Application

Implementing CRUD operations for simple clinic appointment application.

Tools: MySQL, Angular, Spring Boot frameworks.

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app

Attachmate Extra! X-treme Macro Interface

Interface for developing utility programs and macros with Python programming language for Extra! X-treme terminals.

Tools: Python, PyQt5, Extra! X-treme API

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface

Blazing Fruits

Android game checks multitasking and hand-eye coordination.

Tools: Java, Android Studio, libGDX Library

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing fruits

An Indoor Localization Algorithm On FPGA

Multiple RF reader modules were localized by using received signal strength value from stationary RFID tags. Localization algorithm was implemented on an FPGA.

Tools: Verilog, C++, FPGAs

Link: https://web.itu.edu.tr/~orssi/thesis/2015/AlpOran bit.pdf

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Frameworks

- JAVA
- IBM High-Level Assembler Language
- Python
- SQL
- Spring Boot
- Hibernate
- JUnit
- Angular Framework

Tools

- Git
- GitHub / BitBucket
- Relational Databases
- JIRA
- Trello
- CA Clarity PPM

LANGUAGES & TEST SCORES

Turkish: Native or bilingual proficiency **English**: Full professional proficiency

IELTS (International English Language Testing System), Nov 2015

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

Overall Score: 7.5/9

TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), Jul 2015

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

Total Score: 92/120